# **JUAN BERUMEN**

## Senior Full Stack Developer

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Full Stack Developer

04/2024 - Present

# Devsinc

San Francisco, CA

- Implemented React Native for cross-platform mobile application development, expanding the reach of our applications and ensuring a consistent user experience across devices
- Demonstrated expertise in front-end technologies, along with strong proficiency in server-side technologies and frameworks such as JavaScript, Node.js, and Python
- Conducted thorough code reviews to ensure code quality and adherence to coding standards
- Developed and maintained RESTful APIs, microservices, and various database technologies including SQL, MySQL, GraphQL, and web services
- Engaged in all stages of the software development life cycle and contributed to architectural designs
- Promoted a culture of continuous learning by facilitating knowledge sharing and fostering an environment of open and constructive feedback
- Proficiently utilized Git, Trello, Jira, Slack, and Asana for effective project management and collaboration

#### Senior Full Stack Engineer

02/2022 - 03/2024

#### Columbia Sportswear

Portland, OR

- Collaborated with 6 members in designing and implementing scalable web applications using React, Next.js, and Angular
- Developed and launched a robust backend system utilizing modern technologies and frameworks, including Node.js/Express.js and Java/Spring Boot
- Played a key role in designing and optimizing database schemas using MongoDB, and implemented caching mechanisms with Redis
- Utilized serverless architecture to achieve scalability, and AWS Cloud technologies, including Lambda, API Gateway, Cognito, SSM, EC2, CloudFormation, S3, SNS, RDS and EventBridge
- Integrated Apache Kafka to enable real-time data streaming and processing, ensuring high-throughput, fault-tolerant communication between microservices
- Applied Agile methodologies, Test Driven Development and Pair Programming in coding practices, resulting in faster development cycles
- Promoted experience with Kubernetes, Docker and Amazon Web Service

# Senior Full Stack Developer

01/2018 - 01/2022

#### **Albertsons**

Seattle, WA

- Worked on both the backend and frontend of the platform, using PHP(Laravel) and TypeScript(Vue, React, Node.js)
- Integrated third party APIs for the payment gateway setup like PayPal and Stripe, and established email and text messaging services using Sendgrid, Twilio and AWS SES
- Implemented server-side rendering (SSR) to boost application performance and optimize search engine visibility (SEO), thereby enhancing user experience and significantly reducing load times
- Utilized test frameworks such as Jest, Mocha, and Chai to develop and maintain unit and integration tests, ensuring robust and error-free code
- Built robust backend system using Python/Django with the combination of Al Algorithms
- Implemented Elasticsearch to enable fast and scalable search capabilities, improving data retrieval efficiency and enhancing user search experiences with advanced filtering and full-text search functionalities

## Full Stack Developer

09/2016 - 12/2017

#### Uber

San Francisco, CA

- Developed dynamic front-end applications using Vue, React, Tailwind CSS, and JavaScript to develop the user interface to validate the user at the client-side and provide responsive feedback
- Built LAMP stack web applications using MVC PHP frameworks such as Laravel, Symfony
- Leveraged jQuery to streamline DOM manipulation, handle events, and implement AJAX requests for dynamic and responsive web applications
- Performed unit testing and integrated testing for implemented functionality with Jest & PHPUnit to write code faster and improve its quality

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a senior full stack developer with 8 years of experience in web development who has talents in JS/TS, Node, Python and Java.

I strive also to be a cooperative team player who not only learns from others but also can add to the strength of others to improve the overall output of the team

### **SKILLS**

#### Frontend

React/Redux/Hooks · React Native ·

Next.js · Angular · Vue/Vuex

#### Backend

Node.js · Express.js · GraphQL · Laravel ·

Spring Boot · Django

# Storage

 $\mathsf{MySQL} \cdot \mathsf{PostgreSQL} \cdot \mathsf{MongoDB} \cdot \mathsf{Oracle} \cdot \\$ 

Redis · DynamoDB

## **Tools & Platforms**

AWS · Azure · GCP · Docker · Kubernetes ·

Jenkins · Git · Jira · Maven

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor's in Computer Science**

**Antioch University** 

09/2013 - 09/2016

# **VOLUNTEERING**

# **COVID-19 Support Network**

Independent Volunteer Initiative

04/2020 - 06/2020

Developed a platform to connect volunteers with those in need during the pandemic. Contributed as a full-stack developer, focusing on enabling services like grocery deliveries and medical support through Java Spring Boot and React.